A Guide to the Henkel Family Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8653-i
Henkel Family Papers 1800-1829
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8653-i
356 items
Mrs. John Godfrey Miller
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This addition to the papers of the Henkel family was given to the Library by Mrs. John Godfrey Miller of New Market, Virginia, through H.E. Comstock of Winchester, Virginia, on January 10, 1991.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the business, legal, and personal correspondence of the Henkel family of New Market, Virginia, and contains 356 letters (2 Hollinger boxes), 1800-1829, and undated, the majority of which are in German. The correspondents include John Gruber of Hagerstown, Maryland, concerning book purchases and the printing business in New Market; Ambrose Henkel, Golden Spring, Rowan County, North Carolina, and Baltimore, Maryland, where he worked in a bookstore for a time, about family matters, preaching in the Lutheran Church, and book sales; letters from miscellaneous members of the Henkel family; Charles Henkel; Jacob Henkel; Paul Henkel(6 folders of 126 letters); Philip Henkel(5 folders of 110 letters); the business of Samuel & S. Jackson, late David & S. Jackson; Gideon L. Jones; and Samuel Sower & Company.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE
  - Letters from John Gruber, 1806-1823; (2 folders) (Box Box 1)
  - Letters from the Henkel Family, 1814-1818, n.d. (Box Box 1)
  - Letters from Ambrose Henkel, 1801-1818 (Box Box 1)
  - Letters from Charles Henkel, 1817-1821 (Box Box 1)
  - Letters from Jacob Henkel, 1809, 1818 (Box Box 1)
  - Letters from Paul Henkel, 1800-1822, n.d.; (6 folders) (Box Box 1)
  - Letters from Philip Henkel, 1801-1829, n.d.; (5 folders) (Box Box 2)
  - Letters from Samuel & S. Jackson, late David & S. Jackson, 1801-1817 (Box Box 2)
  - Letters from Gideon L. Jones, 1818-1821 (Box Box 2)
  - Letters from Miscellaneous Correspondents, 1802-1816, 1823, 1829 (Box Box 2)
  - Letters from Samuel Sower & Company, 1808-1812 (Box Box 2)